brennancenter.org 2018-12-29

# Privacy Policy | Brennan Center for Justice

**Date Updated: July 5, 2016**

This Privacy Policy describes the types of information that the Brennan Center for Justice at NYU School of Law (“Brennan Center”) may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the website [www.brennancenter.org](http://www.brennancenter.org/) (the “Site”) or donate to the Brennan Center, and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting and disclosing that information. You are advised to consult the “Privacy” link on the Site each time you visit the Site. Your continued use of the Site constitutes your agreement to the Policy, as it may be amended from time to time.

**1\. Information We Collect.**

We may collect personal information from you when you submit it to the Site or donate to the Brennan Center. The following list includes the most common ways that you may provide your personal information to us:

Automatically Collected Data.  We automatically collect and store IP addresses and domain names of visitors’ computers.  We also track the number, frequency, and length of visits to each page.  If you visit our website from another website, we may also identify that source link.  Automatically collected data is used to determine which sections of our website are the most visited and by whom, in order to make our website a more useful resource.

Registration. We do not ask that you register or enter any personal information to access or use most areas of the Site. However, you may choose to subscribe to certain newsletters distributed by the Brennan Center or to join our mailing list, which may require you to enter certain personal information. If you have any questions about modifying or deleting your information, you can contact us directly at [bccommunications@mercury.law.nyu.edu](mailto:bccommunications@mercury.law.nyu.edu).

Donations and Gifts; Secure Transactions. In order to make a donation or other gift, you will be required to provide personal information about yourself.  When you donate via the Site, your donation is processed via Network For Good, and the Brennan Center does not have access to your credit card data.  Other donation information (i.e., your name, address, donation amount) is transmitted to the Brennan Center via a secure connection.   

Communications between you and the Brennan Center. As described in this Policy, you may contact the Brennan Center or subscribe to newsletters and other mailings, and the Brennan Center may respond to your inquiries or request for mailings.  Additionally, when you provide us with your email address and mailing address, we may contact you to ask you to support the Brennan Center. You can choose not to receive such requests by emailing [donations@brennan.law.nyu.edu](mailto:donations@brennan.law.nyu.edu).  If you have opted to receive any of our publications by email, you are able at any time to unsubscribe from that publication by clicking the “unsubscribe” link that appears in the email publication itself.

**2\. Other Information We Collect.**

Cookies; Tracking Mechanisms.  The Brennan Center uses cookies to prepopulate forms for users, to auto-populate forms, and to track user patterns on the Site. These cookies help us understand what parts of the Site are most interesting to our users. The information in the cookie includes a user’s IP address and is transmitted to and stored by Google. You may at any time delete any cookies by using the relevant option of your Internet or mobile browser or by deleting the cookies on your hard drive or mobile device.

We track open rates, click-throughs and the IP address of Site users to measure the effectiveness of our campaigns and discourage fraudulent uses.  We may employ web beacons to help us compile aggregated statistics regarding the operations of the Site.

Analytics. The Brennan Center has implemented Google Analytics to better understand our website visitors and to help refine our online ad campaign strategies.  You can opt-out of Google Analytics by modifying your [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) or by downloading [this browser extension](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). For more information on how Google Analytics may use your data, you may review its policy located at [this link](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

Using the settings of your Internet or mobile browser, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. Consult your browser Help menu or the vendor documentation for your specific software to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you choose to turn off cookies, you may not have access to many features that make your browsing of our Site smoother, and some of our services may not function properly. If you continue to use our Site without changing your settings, you consent to our use of cookies and other tools on the Site.

If you do not want us to collect information about your geographic location, you should disable the technology that transmits this information.

**3\. Use/Sharing of Your Information.**

The Brennan Center may disclose certain personal information to third parties, (i) to manage our website and database with the help of service providers (who are obligated to maintain the confidentiality of any provided personal information), (ii) as part of our normal business operations, (iii) to send you communications about your interactions with us or about features of the Site, or (iv) as required by law or requested by governmental or law enforcement authorities, subpoena, court order or discovery request, or when we otherwise believe in good faith that such disclosure is appropriate in connection with any activity that may violate the law or the rights of others, threaten the safety or security of any person or property (including the Site) or expose us to liability.

In addition, the Brennan Center may occasionally share donor data with organizations that we think may interest our donors (“Sharing Organizations”).  This process is carefully controlled through a third party service provider.  The Sharing Organization does not see our data, nor does it know what information is contained therein other than the names and contact information of those individuals who respond to its communication.  If you prefer that we not include your data for sharing in this manner may opt out by (a) sending an email to the “opt-out” mailbox identified in the donation confirmation email if the donation is made online; (b) sending an email to [donations@brennan.law.nyu.edu](mailto:donations@brennan.law.nyu.edu), or (c) checking the relevant box on a donation slip received in the mail.  Please allow up to six weeks for processing of such requests.

  **4\. Other Websites.**

This Policy applies only to the Site. If you visit any unaffiliated website linked to the Site (for example, Twitter, Facebook or other social media sites), you are subject to that entity’s own privacy policies, which we do not control or monitor. You should review the privacy policies of all third-party websites before you visit them. The Brennan Center has not reviewed all of the sites linked to this Site and it makes no representations or warranties as to the privacy practices, functioning or content of any sites linked to this Site.

**5\. International Use.**

This Privacy Policy is intended to meet the laws and regulations of the United States, and despite the global nature of the Internet, the Brennan Center makes no claims that the Site is appropriate or may be viewed or used outside the United States. Furthermore, our databases are located in the United States. By sending us your data, you consent to its transfer to and storage within the United States. Irrespective of the country in which you reside or from which you access the Site, you authorize the Brennan Center to use your personal information in the United States and any other country where it operates. Access to the Site from countries or territories where such access is illegal or contrary to applicable rules or regulations is prohibited. Those who access the Site from outside the United States do so on their own initiative and are responsible for compliance with local laws, rules and regulations. 

**6\. Children’s Privacy.**

The Site is not targeted toward, and we do not seek or desire to collect information from, children under the age of 13. Therefore, we will not knowingly request information from persons under such age. If we become aware that we have collected any personal information from children under 13, we will promptly use commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information.  If you believe that we might have personal information of a child under 13, please contact us at [brennancenter@nyu.edu](mailto:brennancenter@nyu.edu).

**7.** **Notice Procedures.**

Please send all Privacy Policy-related communications to [brennancenter@nyu.edu](mailto:brennancenter@nyu.edu). To the fullest extent permitted by law, you agree to receive all legally required notices regarding this Privacy Policy or any privacy or security breaches relating to the Site at the email address you use to contact the Site.

**8\. Governing Law.**

You agree that this Policy and your use of this Site shall be governed in all respects by the laws of the State of New York. Any dispute relating to this Policy and your use of this Site shall be resolved solely in the state or federal courts located in the State and County of New York.
